

# Alexey Saechnikov

iOS Developer

Passionate iOS developer who gets great satisfaction from taking an app through the production cycle to it's launch. Has experience of leading teams of 3-5 people and is particularly interested in building or improving a stable architecture for applications to improve their scalability. Fast and enthusiastic learner with interesting and diverse experiences.

MINSK, BELARUS

iOS, OS X, Watch OS, tvOS, CI and CD.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

TECHNICAL SKILLS YEARS OF EXPERIENCE PROFICIENCY

Swift 4 (since 2016)  $\star\star\star\star\star$ 

Objective C 8 (since 2012)  $\star \star \star \star \star$ 

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Lead iOS Developer (remote)

2017 - 2020

**Tapp Solutions** 

https://www.tappsolutions.com/

- Planning and implementing project architecture
- Developing frameworks to reuse in all complany applications
- Support existing applications

## Freelance Developer

2015 - current

Upwork, personal connections

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~0164318e9deae07ccb

- Searching for new clients
- Preparing specifications
- Planning application architecture
- · Gathering and managing developers team
- · Developing and integrating applications and systems

iOS Developer	2012 - 2015

#### VironIT

#### http://vironit.com

- Creating iOS applications and services
- Deploying apps
- Managing developers team
- Interviewing new candidates for developer job
- Teaching junior developers

#### **SharePoint Administrator**

2011 - 2012

#### BSUIR

#### http://bsuir.by

- Setting up SharePoint workflow system
- SharePoint instance servicing
- Documents management automatization
- Teaching users
- Conferences speaker

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES**

Bachelor's degree BELARUSIAN STATE UNIVERSITY OF INFORMATICS AND RADIOELECTRONICS Electronic Computing	2007 - 2012
High School Education COLLEGE-PREPARATORY SCHOOL Mathematics, Physics	2005 - 2007
Primary Education	1996 - 2005

## **LANGUAGES**

PREPARATORY SCHOOL

English Advanced

Russian Native or bilingual